

ANTHONY DAVIS

Anthony_Davis89@icloud.com | 470.514.9560 | Atlanta, GA 30341

Summary

Senior IT Program Manager with a background in application development offering highly credible technical leadership to direct multi-functional project teams engaged in full system development and implementation in high tech environments. Experienced overseeing diverse teams of developers, analysts and quality professionals engaged in complex projects with budgets up to \$10M. Solid understanding of project management tools. Project Management Professional certified in Scrum, Agile, and Six Sigma Yellow Belt methodologies.

Areas of **Expertise**

- JavaScript/MongoDB/Express/React/Nodejs SDLC Implementation
- HTML/CSS/JQUERY
- Restful API's/SQL/DB2
- PEGA/JIRA/Confluence
- Product Ownership
- Microsoft Office Suite
- IT Infrastructure
- Azure Cloud
- Scrum/Agile Methodologies

- Database Administration
- Project/Program Management
- Resource Optimization
- Executive Leadership & Training
- Application Development
- Performance Tracking & Reporting
- Change Management
- Business Requirements Gathering

Experience

Sr. Technical Program Manager/Software Engineer

01/2015 - Current

Primerica | Duluth, GA

- Fostered relationships with C-Suite executives and management staff while assuring satisfaction with project, process, and outcome to drive to the business case; hand-picked by C-level leadership to undergo executive leadership training at UGA.
- Appointed to the Digital Transformation Champions board consisting of 12 technologists and 600+ IT professionals that oversaw the company's digital transformations efforts; developed change management plans minimizing employee resistance and accelerating adoption.
- Eliminated errors by implementing quality measures and procedures that improved bug testing and evangelized them within the division resulting in multiple seamless releases.
- Utilized extensive technical background to coordinate the development of a new database and two new user interfaces Planned and led the IT Infrastructure Library (ITIL) implementation effort.
- Saved the company \$40K a month by eliminating the need for paper processing.
- Successfully led the effort to convert several waterfalls teams to agile teams and led the effort to train and educate the IT department on scrum methodologies.
- Documented research findings and prepared polished reports highlighting results and potential improvement strategies; designed product features and enhancements that improved production performance by 30% and significantly reduced error rates.

IT Program Manager

01/2014 - 01/2015

Verizon Wireless | Alpharetta, GA

 Coordinated with Product Managers and Scrum Masters to assist with training, mentoring, and professional development of 15 Associates; recognized by management for

- consistently meeting performance goals, serving as proxy for user during development, conducting root cause analysis, and creating training and implementation plans to improve productivity and accurately design workflow.
- Secured optimal pricing to support technology solution project completion within budget parameters, successfully managing \$4M in IT assets for new data facilities.
- Researched and analyzed customer/employee data from monthly surveys to support
 organization's lean initiatives; successfully implemented a workflow process that reduced
 manager approval, improved customer and employee satisfaction, and increased retention
 rates.
- Provided technology consultation for growing businesses, making recommendations and upgrading existing systems; achieved client vision and objectives through effective strategy development and execution in coordination with management teams.

Associate Application Developer/ Program Manager

01/2012 - 01/2014

Heritage Bank of the South | Albany, GA

- Managed a team of 10 IT professionals (5 developers, 1 project manager, 2 QAs, and 2 BAs);
 administered \$2M operational budget in development of programs and services to meet
 needs of diverse community members of various racial and socio-economic backgrounds.
- Contributed to the development of a new chatbot feature, mobile deposit feature, in-app notifications, and several high impact banking features; significantly improved UX and increased customer engagement.
- Assessed project risks and devised mitigation actions encompassing close attention to contracts and service level agreements by subcontractors and vendors, external dependencies and potential roadblocks.
- Enhanced development and drove continuous improvement of project delivery process by providing strong program leadership; implemented a more efficient workflow system which boosted productivity rates by 24% and reduced project completion time by as much as 34%.
- Leveraged Agile methodologies to move development lifecycle rapidly through initial
 prototyping to enterprise-quality testing and final implementation; pioneered the
 implementation of a new product line which added \$300K+ in monthly sales for the
 company.

Education and Training

Executive Leadership Training

2020

2018

University of Georgia

M.S: Information Technology

Middle Georgia State University | Macon, GA

2015

B.S: Supply Chain Management & Logistics Albany State University | Albany, GA

Certifications

- Full-Stack Bootcamp: Georgia Tech, 2021
- Executive Leadership Training: University of Georgia, 2020
- Certified Scrum Master: 2020
- Pega Certified Business Architect: 2020
- DB2 Programming Certification: Marist College, 2018
- Six Sigma Yellow Belt